<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reel Movement Blog</title>
    <description>check out my blog
</description>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 09:29:03 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 09:29:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>PRINCIPLES OF TRAINING</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
We all have been in a position where we want to get in better shape but we just have no idea where to begin. At Reel Movement you will not only train hard but you will also train smart. That means getting a better understanding of the human body and how it responds to exercise. To better understand how the body reacts to exercise we need to breakdown some basic principles of training. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Principle of overload &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The body constantly adapts to the pressure that is exerted on it. If you intend to continue to see training adaptations you must place additional stress on the body. For example, you can increase the intensity of an exercise by decreasing rest time, adding additional weight, or progressing from a static movement to a dynamic one. It is important that you understand that the intensity should be raised progressively and cautiously in order to prevent overtraining.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Principle of Specificity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The body adapts to the specific demand placed on it. For, example you should not expect to lift heavier weights by running three miles. You should expect to improve at running three miles. If your goal is to improve your cardiovascular system than running is a good approach but if your goal is to improve lean muscle mass resistance training would be the best option. You should include different types of training because they all offer unique adaptations.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Principle of Individualization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We are all individuals and thus we have to take into account each person’s response to exercise. There is no exercise program that is one size fits all. Understanding your body is a key principle of training smart. For instance, you may need to remain at a lower intensity program for slightly longer than another individual or you may progress faster. Once you become conscious of your own body you will continue to progress safely and efficiently. 


“Remember train hard and train smart!”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founder and CEO of Reel Movement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;script&quot;&gt; Daniel Ponce &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 07:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/principles</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/principles</guid>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is The Core and Why is it Important?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Core training has become extremely popular over the past several years, but why is it so important and what are the potential benefits of training the core? The core musculature is not just made up of the rectus abdominus and the internal and external oblique, but a much more extensive network of muscles. The core is broken down into three systems.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Local Stabilization System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The local core stabilizers are muscles that attach directly to the spine and aid in stability in between each vertebra.  Some muscles that comprise the local stabilization system are the transverse abdominus, internal oblique, and the multifidus. This system overall contributes in increasing segmental spinal stability.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Global Stabilization System &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The muscles of the global stabilization system attach the pelvis to the spine. Some of the major muscles of this system include the quadratus lumborum, psoas major, and the external oblique. Its main function is to provide stability between the pelvis and the spine and transfer loads between the upper and lower extremities. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Movement System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The muscles of this system attach the spine and/or pelvis to the extremities. The movement systems primary muscles are the latissimus dorsi, hip flexors, hamstrings, and quadriceps. When it comes to the core the movement system provides dynamic stabilization when the body is performing functional activities. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;	
The core ultimately provides stabilization throughout the spine and hips allowing for optimum joint movement. A strengthened core reduces the risk of injury, improves function and performance, and improves neuromuscular control and stability. A good core program focuses on function and movement rather than just quantity.  So, in your workout include some core exercises and watch how much more your performance improves
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder and CEO of Reel Movement&lt;/p&gt;

Daniel Ponce
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 07:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/core-training</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/core-training</guid>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
